Lindsey Lauria

Address Irvine, CA 92603

Phone 714-552-9511

Email ljjlauria@mac.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/lindseyjjlauria

GitHub https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan

Website http://www.jeejan.com

Summary

User-focused Front End Developer with a strong technical background in both design and development of responsive and accessible user interfaces. Communicating effectively with both programmers and product stakeholders is a skill I have developed through my experience and lends itself to creating the best user experiences while considering business requirements and resource budgets.

Technical Skills

Agile, SDLC, JIRA, Git, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, BrowserStack, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, Web APIs, REST APIs, Express, NodeJS, NPM - Node Package Manager, MYSQL, OOJS - object oriented JavaScript, web forms, form validation, accessibility, WCAG, WAI-ARIA, rapid prototyping, interaction design, Sketch, Photoshop.

Projects

Favor Trader

Favor Trader is a neighborhood bartering platform for favors. It contains an Activity Feed where all user's favors needs are listed. To begin trading, each user will need to log in or sign up and create a user profile. This application is built with Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Heroku, Bootstrap, Bootswatch, jQuery, Google Maps API

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/Favor-Trader

Deployed Project https://favortrader-ll.herokuapp.com/

Study Buddy

The application provides the user with the ability to gather learning resources and coding solutions for various learning styles by connecting to StackExchange and YouTube APIs. Uses REST APIs and JSON.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/project-one

Deployed Project https://lindseyjeejan.github.io/project-one/

Weather Dashboard

Single page application consisting of a timed quiz for the user developed with JavaScript. Uses JavaScript, Bootstrap, JSON and OpenWeather API.

URL https://github.com/LindseyJeeJan/weather-dashboard

Deployed Project https://lindseyjeejan.github.io/weather-dashboard/

Experience

Interaction Designer • Ultimate Kronos Group, Incorporated • Irvine, CA • 05/2012 ~ Current

- Create and maintain visual design system while producing a large volume of reusable design components and responsive full page layouts, coded by hand in HTML5 and CSS3 using Bootstrap framework.
- Develop and troubleshoot user interactions written in JavaScript, jQuery and jQuery UI.
- Solve cross platform and cross browser display issues to maximize acceptance across supported platforms and browsers, performed cross browser testing in BrowserStack.
- Review application improvements to ensure technology is utilizing the latest browser supported features. Perform iterative front end design reviews ensure development is completed on time and prevent costly code fixes.
- Lead, defined and implemented accessibility standards initiative through the translation of WAI-ARIA accessibility standards into technical tasks to conform to a WCAG 2.0 AA acceptance criteria.
- Participate in continuous collaboration with programmers, Product Managers and stakeholders to
 provide technical guidance for best practices on front end architecture. Evaluate technical
 considerations along with business requirements to recommend how to achieve a successful
 design within the time budget.
- Design features in Sketch, produce wireframes, clickable prototypes and multiple deliverable formats for use across organization. Lead design presentations to clearly articulate concepts to technical and non-technical audiences.

Web Developer • Glidewell Laboratories • Newport Beach, CA • 08/2006 ~ 05/2012

- Coded and maintained corporate websites using search engine optimization and implementation
 of Google Analytics to measure traffic and visitor trends. Used Photoshop to extract digital print
 graphics and turn them into interactive, media rich websites with Adobe Flash.
- Developed front end of customer facing application along side team of programmers for an ASP.NET application using Microsoft TFS.

Education

California Polytechnic State University • San Luis Obispo, CA • 1997 ~ 2001 Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, concentration in Management Information Systems.

UCI Division of Continuing Education • Irvine, CA • 2021 Certificate, Full Stack Developer

Department of Homeland Security Office of Accessible Systems & Technology Certificate, Trusted Tester